Guide to the Gleysteen Family Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Diaries and Notebooks, Series II
  - Theodora Culver Gleysteen and William H. Gleysteen
    - TCG diaries, 1950, 1951, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - TCG journal containing notes about hosted events and records of mail received and responses, 1950-1970 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - TCG diaries, 1953, 1954, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - TCG diaries, 1956, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - TCG diaries, 1958, 1959, 1959 December - 1960 January (Box 28, Folder 2)
      Third volume dates from December 1959-January 1960
    - TCG diaries, 1960, 1961, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      1961 diary is labeled "TCG's Russian Trip"
    - TCG diaries, 1963, 1964, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - TCG diaries, 1966, 1967, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - TCG diary, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - TCG diary, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - TCG diary, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - TCG diary, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - TCG diary, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Annie J. S. Wallace Culver
    - Diary, 1885 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1891 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1892 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Diary, 1893 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Diary, 1894 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Diary with two years of entries, 1895-1896 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Diary, 1897 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1898 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1899 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Diary, 1900 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Diary, 1901 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1902 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1903 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      Volume is labeled "This Diary tells about the founding of the Jenkintown Day Nursery, March 4, 1903"
    - Diary, 1904 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Diary, 1905 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1906 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1907 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Expense book, 1908 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1908 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1909 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Travel journal - "Across the Atlantic", 1909 June 12 - August 5 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Diary, 1910 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Diary, 1911 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1912 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Diaries, 1913, 1914 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Diaries, 1915, 1916 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Diaries, 1917, 1918, 1919 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Diaries, 1920, 1921, 1922 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Diaries, 1923, 1924 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Diaries, 1925, 1926 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Diary, 1927 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Diaries, one volume a travel journal "My Travels Abroad", 1928, 1928-1929 May 19 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Two diaries, one volume a journal of trip from China through Europe, "My Travels Abroad"; two notebooks of general observations, 1929 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1930 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1931 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Diary, 1932 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Diary, 1933 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Loose journal pages detailing travels, 1933-1937 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Loose journal pages detailing travels, 1933-1937 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Diaries, 1934, 1935 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Diaries, notebook (1937), 1937, 1938, 1939 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Diaries, 1940, 1941 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Diaries, notebook/planner (1943), 1942, 1943 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Diaries, 1944, 1945 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Diaries, 1946, 1947 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Diaries, 1948, 1949 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Diaries, diary/notebook of "important dates", 1950, 1951 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Diaries, 1952, 1953 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Diaries, undated notebook, 1954, 1955, no date (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Helen P. Scott
    - Five-year diaries, 1918-1922, 1923-1927 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Five-year diaries, 1928-1932, 1933-1937 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Notebook, 1944 (Box 41, Folder 3)
- Writings, Series III
  - Theodora Culver Gleysteen and William H. Gleysteen
    - "The Triangle Club": sets of short stories written by TCG and friends (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - TCG: "Compositions and Exercises" - written while at Chelten Hills School, 1907 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - TCG: Essays from time at Stevens School, 1907-1909 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - TCG: "Jeremiah Work"—notes about the book of Jeremiah, probably written at Bible Teachers Training School, ca. 1911-1913 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - TCG: "The Song of a Spring", 1913 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - TCG: Autobiography (up to time at University of Pennsylvania), 1917 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - TCG: Copy of and translation of "The Garden of the Hundred Grasses" by Lu Hsun (prepared during internment in Peking), 1941-1943 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - TCG and WHG: "Missionaries and Reading", 1946 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - TCG and WHG: "Channeling Literature to Missionaries on the Fields", 1946 (Box 42, Folder 9)
      Enclosures: name cards
    - TCG: "Psychology of Family Relations" (written in response to Elizabeth Hobart's request); "American Family Life Outside the United States", 1946, 1954 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - WHG: "Timothy Tinfang Lew", 1946 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - TCG: Research on Dr. Sheldon Jackson, 1948 (Box 42, Folder 12)
      Material compiled while TCG was at the Presbyterian Historical Society: bibliographic notes, notes on writings, correspondence, news clippings, and writings
    - TCG: Writings on travels: "Round the World by Freighter and Plane" (1950); "Russian Duet" (1962); "A Modern Visit to Ancient Russia" (1962), 1950, 1962 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - TCG: Writings on Truth Hall: "Winter Relief"; "Truth Hall's School for Street Urchins", 1962 (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Annie Wallace Culver
    - "Maidenhood", ca. 1884 (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Untitled religious writings, 1954 (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Klazina Gleysteen Newell
    - "A Child, an Owl, and a Cow", 1950 (Box 42, Folder 17)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, Series IV
  - Genealogical documentation
    - Culver family genealogical information and "Notes about Birth and Life of Rev. A. Culver" (1819-1911) –TCG's grandfather (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - Culver family information and Gleysteen family genealogy notes (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - Gleysteen family genealogy and biographical documentation, as compiled by Dirk Gleysteen and Nicholas Gleysteen (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - Biographical material / memorabilia
    - Theodora Culver Gleysteen
      - Collected drawings, no date (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - "Love and Friendship" by Dr. Frederick Dripps of Stevens School; includes postcard from TBC, 1882 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Early drawings by TCG, 1901-1906 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - Reports, bills, prize, notes from school years, 1906-1916 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - "Exercises for Drawing" at Chelten Hills School, circa 1907 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - Name cards; postcards; "Active Members Pledge"; picture of Martha Torrey, 1909 (Box 45, Folder 6)
      - Stevens School: Senior prom booklet; "The School Review" cover; "The Record of Class of 1910" (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - Bible Teachers Training School: notes, pamphlet, 1911 (Box 45, Folder 8)
      - Related to PCUSA: pew receipt, doctor examination note, notary note, 1912-1917 (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - PCUSA missionary dinner, 1917 (Box 45, Folder 9)
      - Invitations for wedding of Theodora and William Gleysteen, 1920 (Box 45, Folder 10)
      - Newspaper clippings about Mother of the Year award, 1953 (Box 45, Folder 11)
      - Pennsylvania State University course completion certificate, 1959 (Box 45, Folder 12)
      - Certificate of vaccination, 1965 (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - Newspaper clippings about World Day of Prayer, 1968 (Box 45, Folder 13)
      - Wilson College Centennial Citation: photo, program, correspondence, certificate, news clipping, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 14)
      - 80th birthday: list of gifts; "Vignettes of 80 Years" by Helen Scott, 1973 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - William H. Gleysteen
      - WHG: obituaries, will and estate documents, Peking Church memorial service program, "Memorial Minute" written by Board of Foreign Missions of the PCUSA, 1948 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - William H. Gleysteen: Pastoral documents; birth record correspondence; medical exam; University of Michigan Alumni Association documents, 1904-1947 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Annie Wallace Culver / Theodore B. Culver
      - TBC: drawing books, 1869 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - TBC: Grammar School Commencement, 1877 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - AWC: material related to Girls' Normal School, Philadelphia, 1884-1955 (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - AWC: "26th Annual Report of the Camden Home for Friendless Children"; bread judgment reports, 1890-1891 (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - AWC: Pictures, invitations, news clippings of Jenkintown Day Nursery, 1910-1972 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - TBC: Newspaper obituaries, 1928 (Box 46, Folder 6)
      - AWC: Certificate from Pennsylvania Museum of Art, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 7)
      - AWC: newspaper clips of Rotary Club meritorious service; "Dial Phone Makes Debut Better"; obituaries, 1955-1957 (Box 46, Folder 8)
      - Grace Presbyterian Church memorial service bulletins, 1961 (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - Household inventory; mailed ad for "Thomas Stevens, Coventry & London", No date (Box 46, Folder 10)
      - TBC and AWC: metal name plates, No date (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Gleysteen children
      - Klazina Gleysteen Newell: newspaper obituary, 1956 (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - Klazina: "The One Act Play Contest" program, 1941 (Box 46, Folder 12)
      - Culver Gleysteen: newspaper clippings re. his diplomatic service, 1943, 1973 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Helen P. Scott
      - Newspaper clippings regarding China, SS Gripsholm, 1941-1944 (Box 46, Folder 14)
      - Periodical articles regarding China, SS Gripsholm, 1943-1944 (Box 46, Folder 15)
      - "Second Repatriation Conference"; "Forward for Young People"; "Pastor's Aid Society" speech outline; church bulletin, 1943-1944 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Travel documentation
    - Theodora Culver Gleysteen: itinerary for train trip from Philadelphia to Vancouver, 1917 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - TCG: flight log and world tour map; list of passengers, 1950, 1952 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - TCG: list of passengers, trip notes, postcards with notes, bills, correspondence about passport, 1959-1960 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - TCG: bills, itinerary, notes, 1961 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Annie Wallace Culver: three passports, 1928-1929, 1933-1934, 1937 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - AWC:: re. trip to Blowing Rock, North Carolina; includes correspondence with Fee Memorial Institute, Nicholasville, KY, 1930 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Trip to India, Middle East, Egypt, Italy, France, Spain: pictures, itinerary, notes, 1934 (Box 43, Folder 12-13)
    - AWC: trip with Helen P. Scott to China and South East Asia, ca. 1934 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Helen P. Scott: journey artifacts, incl. passport, Brazil pamphlets, vaccination certification, 1943 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Expense records
    - Annie Wallace Culver: two expense books, 1890, 1931 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Theodore B. Culver: TBC: one expense book, 1893 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - TBC: Bills, receipts, correspondence on expenditures, 1905-1919 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - AWC: receipt book for servants' wages, 1903-1906 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - AWC: one expense book, 1933-1934 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - AWC: one loose expense book, 1950-1957 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Book of properties and their value for Culver family members, 1902-1931 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Helen P. Scott: check, correspondence about money, 1944 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Collected material
    - News clippings regarding death of Queen Victoria, 1901 (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - "The Mentor: Famous English Poets" periodical, 1913 (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - Newspaper clippings regarding China and Japan, 1919-1947 (Box 46, Folder 19)
    - "1930 Guide to Peking"; Peking Utility Book; Peiping Address Book; "Guide to the Christian Institutions of Peking Where British and Americans are at Work", 1930-1947, no date (Box 46, Folder 20)
    - "The Presbyterian Mission Peking" (1932); "History of Grace Presbyterian Church in the Borough of Jenkintown, Pennsylvania" (1965), 1932, 1965 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - "Peking American School Chinese Reader" Vols. II and III, 1935 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - F.C. Sumner writings, 1943, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 3)
      Includes: "Review: A History of Medical Psychology (G. Zilboorg and G.W. Henry)"; "Some Factors Influencing a Group of Negroes in their Estimation of the Intelligence and Personality-Wholesomeness of Negro Subjects"
    - Articles about Asia, 1943, 1953 (Box 47, Folder 4)
      Includes:"Construction of the Greater East Asia Co-Prosperity Sphere" (1943); "Communiques Issued by the Imperial General Headquarters (Since the Outbreak of the Greater East Asia War)" (1943); "Archives of the Chinese Art Society of America" (1953)
    - Timothy Tingfang Lew: obituaries, 1947 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Map of world mounted on black paper, No date (Box OV1)
    - "North China Standard, Peking's Daily Newspaper. Neighbor Nations Pictorial Supplement", No date (Box OV1)
- Photographs, Series V
  - Albums
    - Two albums, 1917, 1917-1918 (Box 48, Folder 1)
      1) Jenkintown home, travels to China, Peking; 2) Peking: missionaries, Chinese people, landscapes and buildings
    - Two albums, 1918-1919, 1920 (Box 48, Folder 2)
      1) Peking: buildings, people, school, church; trip to country: buildings, landscapes, people; Mongolia: caravan, people; 2) Outing at summer palace: family, friends; trip to America (Jenkintown, Alton): family, wedding of TCG and WHG; Peitaiho; Truth Hall, Peking
    - Two albums, 1921, 1922 (Box 48, Folder 3)
      1: Peking: family, Truth Hall faculty; Shuntefu: soup kitchen and hungry people; Famine District: people; Paotingfu: refugees; Western Hills: missionaries, TCG, family, Chinese people; Camping Trip in Kalgan: family 2: Peking: the house, family, Truth Hall boys; Paotingfu: mission meeting; Peitaiho: scenery, family
    - Two albums, 1923, 1924 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      1: Peking: family, friends, Truth Hall; America (Alton, Jenkintown): family 2: America (Jenkintown, Alton, Honolulu): family, friends; Peking: family
    - Two albums, 1925, 1926 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      1: Peking: family and friends, Truth Hall, house; trip to Miao Feng Shan; Peitaiho: scenery, friends, family, Chinese people 2: Peking: buildings, family, Truth Hall; Peitaiho: family
    - Two albums, 1927, 1928-1929 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      1: Peking: family, friends, Chinese people and scenery; trip to Pai Hua Shan: scenery, family and friends; Jenkintown: family 2: Peking: family, friends, Chinese scenery, car; Peitaiho: family; Western Hills: family
    - Two albums, 1929-1930, 1931 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      1: Peking: family, friends; Wo Fo Ssu: family, friends 2: Peking: family; trip on S.S. Saarbrucken: family, scenery along the way (Singapore, Sumatra, Italy, Germany, Switzerland); Jenkintown: family
    - Two albums, 1932, 1933 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      1: Jenkintown: family, friends; Alton: family; trip back to China (S.S. Empress of Japan): family, staff; Peking: family, friends, Truth Hall folks, Chinese folks; Western Hills: family, Chinese folks 2: Peking: scenery, Truth Hall, family, friends; Peitaiho: family, scenery, friends; Western Hills: family, Chinese folks, scenery, friends
    - Two albums, 1934-1935, 1936 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      1: 1934: Peking: family, friends; Peitaiho: family, friends; 1935: Peitaiho: family; Ch'ung-T'zu: family, friends; Peking: family, friends 2: Peitaiho: scenery, new cottage, family, friends, Chinese people, Alice and Scott Morton's wedding; Peking: family, friends, Truth Hall, Chinese people
    - Two albums, 1937, 1938 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      1: Peking: family, friends, Chinese folks, scenery; Western Hills: family, friends, Chinese people, scenery; Peitaiho: same; includes Mrs. Culver 2: Peking: family, Truth Hall; Liaoyang: Alice, Scott, and son Michael with family; Peitaiho: family
    - Two albums, 1939, 1940 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - One album, 1946 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      Jenkintown: Klazina and Bob Newell's wedding; obituary of Bob Newell
  - Loose photos
    - Portraits: family
      - Theodora Culver Gleysteen (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - William Henry Gleysteen (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - Alice Gleysteen (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Theodore Gleysteen (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - Anne Gleysteen (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - Klazina Gleysteen (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Culver Gleysteen (Box 51, Folder 7-8)
      - Billy Gleysteen (Box 51, Folder 9)
      - Dirk Gleysteen (Box 51, Folder 10)
      - Annie Wallace Culver (Box 51, Folder 11)
      - Theodore Baker Culver (Box 51, Folder 12)
      - Henry Wallace (Box 51, Folder 13)
      - R.R. Gleysteen, John Gleysteen, and Klazina van der Linden Gleysteen (Box 51, Folder 14)
      - Cynthia Gleysteen Zwemer (Box 51, Folder 15)
      - "Oobie" Gleysteen (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - Portraits: friends, colleagues
      - Friends and colleagues in China (Box 51, Folder 17)
        Includes: Mrs. Liu, Miss Li, Chao Changfen, Mrs. Ch'en, Y.T. Lo, Mr. Fu Ju P'ei, Ching Nainai, Dr. W.A.P. Martin
      - Rev. William Boyd and Albert Barnes Boyd (Box 51, Folder 18)
      - Mr. and Mrs. John Kenworthy (Box 51, Folder 19)
      - Mr. and Mrs. Reuben Kenworthy (Box 51, Folder 20)
      - Robert McKee, cousin Kate McKee, Daniel McKee (Box 51, Folder 21)
      - William Ferguson, Thomas B. Harper, Margaret Carnwath (Box 51, Folder 22)
      - Stevens School Class of 1910: includes both portraits and class pictures (Box 51, Folder 23)
      - Unidentified (Box 51, Folder 24)
    - Group photos
      - Family / friends in China
        - Adults: WHG, TCG, AWC, Helen Scott, Cynthia Zwemer (Box 52, Folder 1)
        - Adults and Children: Gleysteens (Box 52, Folder 2)
        - Children: Gleysteens (Box 52, Folder 3)
        - Family with friends (Box 52, Folder 4)
        - Family with Truth Hall faculty and students (Box 52, Folder 5)
        - WHG and TCG with Truth Hall faculty and students (Box OV1)
        - Family with other colleagues, friends; includes pictures from WHG memorial in Peking (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - Family in United States
        - Culver extended family and Gleysteen immediate family (Box 52, Folder 7)
          Including Cynthia Gleysteen Zwemer, AWC, cousins Lizzie and Belle Jamison, Torreys
        - Gleysteen family in Alton, Iowa (Box 52, Folder 8)
        - WHG, TCG, Culver, and Billy (Box OV1)
        - WHG in college group photos and TCG in early church photo (Box 52, Folder 9)
        - Class of 1910 Stevens School group picture (Box OV1)
        - Reunion of 1910 class of Stevens School, 1960 (TCG) (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Scenes
      - In China
        - People (Box 52, Folder 11-12)
        - Animals (Box 52, Folder 13)
        - Buildings (Box 52, Folder 14)
        - Other structures: bridges, statues, walls (Box 52, Folder 15)
        - Nature (Box 52, Folder 16)
        - Photo negatives (Box 52, Folder 17)
      - In United States
        - 201 Greenwood Avenue, Jenkintown, PA house (Box 52, Folder 18)
      - Travel
        - Postcards from Gleysteens to Annie Wallace Culver (Box 53, Folder 1)
        - Miscellaneous photos of TCG, family (Box 53, Folder 2)
        - Russia trip (Box 53, Folder 3)
        - TCG and Helen Scott trip to Far East (Box 53, Folder 3)
      - Religious art photos
        - Chinese Christian art pictures, black and white (Box 53, Folder 4-5)
        - Chinese Christian art pictures in color; picture of buildings on sea (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Bound photo compilations
    - "The China Gleysteens" (Box OV1)
    - "The China Gleysteens 1916-1928" (Box OV1)
    - "The China Gleysteens 1929-1940" (Box OV1)